# 它这个面是一斤 高筋特筋
This is 1jin (500g) of flour
# 一斤（面粉）酵母放三克
3 grams of yeast goes into 1jin(500g) of flour
# 泡打粉五克
5 grams of baking powder
# 我先把它给搅匀了
Mix well
# 这样的话发的时候快
So that the dough will rise quicker
# 这时候咱们给它加水 七两水
Then add 7 liang (350g) water
# 河南的水煎包好吃
Henan's pan fried buns are so delicious
# 咱们和面的时候
It is fine
# 把这个水给它
To pour in all of the
# 一次性倒上也行
Water in one go
# 就慢慢的给它做成面搓也可以
Adding the water in slowly is fine as well
# 和完了还饧不饧
Are we resting the dough after mixing it?
# 发一下基本上就是十五六分钟二十分钟
We will let it rest and rise. 15-20mins is enough
# 为什么不能让它发起来
Why can't we let it rise completely?
# 第一 咱们等一下做水煎包的时候
First since when we are cooking the buns
# 还要在水里面
They will cook in water
# 它得煎二次胀发
So it will rise for a second time then
# 这个时候
It will rise
# 它发的是正好的
perfectly once cooked
# 如果说你要是提前给它发出来
If you rise it perfectly before cooking
# 发（时间）正常的时候（面）会发酸
The dough will taste a bit sour after it's cooked
# 行吗 二伯 行
What do you think, Erbai? Good to go? - Yes!
# 盖上 别干了
Cover the dough so that it doesn't dry out
# 一是别干了
Cover it to prevent it from drying out
# 二是它一会就发了
But also it will rise very quickly
# 下一步
Next step
# 这是啥馅儿嘞
What kind of filling is this?
# 这个是牛肉
This is beef
# 而且是三七（比例）
And the lean/fat ratio is 3 to 7
# 这样的话肥瘦均匀的时候
A good ratio between the fat and the lean
# 它吃的东西比较好吃
Will make the food taste better
# 有口感
And also improve the texture
# 这样咱们就做河南最传统的一个
We will make the most traditional buns from
# 薛湖镇的牛肉
Xuehuzhen, Henan. The filling is a mixture of beef,
# 胡萝卜粉条水煎包
carrots, glass noodles.
# 这好 好吃
That sounds amazing
# 咱先给他切个姜末
Let's mince up some ginger
# 豫中平原的美食
The delicacy from the Henan plateau region
# 还很有特色 开封也好
is very unique, like the dishes from Kaifeng,
# 郑州也好
Zhengzhou,
# 商丘也好
Shangqiu,
# 还有长远
and Changyuan
# 还有洛阳水席
Also Luoyang Shui Xi, Luoyang Water Banquet
# 每个地区都有它的特色的美食
Every area has their unique dishes
# 这时候再加一点姜末
Now adding in the minced ginger
# 而且各地的美食
And the dishes from the different regions
# 有时候同样一个菜名
Might share the same name
# 烹调方法可能还有些区别
But the cooking methods can be slightly different
# 在加点葱花
Now adding some chopped scallions
# 这时候咱们切完葱再切点胡萝卜
Let's chop up some carrots after the scallions
# 你看河南咱们听到的
Ji Dan Guan Bing, egg filled pancakes,
# 鸡蛋灌饼 这好吃
is also from Henan and is very delicious.
# 还有胡辣汤
Also Hulatang, Peppery spicy soup
# 铁锅蛋
Tie Guo Dan, Henan style egg cooked in iron pan
# 这河南老菜了
are all traditional Henan dishes
# 下次你做一铁锅蛋
Next time you should teach us how to make Tie Guo Dan
# 好嘞
Deal!
# 包括咱道口的烧鸡
There is also Daokou Shao Ji, braised chicken from Daokou
# 这道口烧鸡好吃
Oh Daokou Shao Ji is so delicious
# 你下回来一道口烧鸡怎么样
You should also teach us how to make Daokou Shao Ji
# 行没问题
No problem
# 切着胡萝卜的时候
When chopping the carrot
# 不要贴的太细
Make sure to not cut it too finely
# 太小的肉跟馅里边
If the pieces are too small
# 最后它吃不出来胡萝卜味儿
You won't be able to taste it in the filling
# 刚才泡好了粉条
We have soaked the glass noodles just now
# 这是河南的红薯粉
This is sweet potato glass noodles from Henan
# 泡的时候 咱可以用温水
You can use warm water when soaking it
# 五六十度（就行）
50 or 60 degrees celcius is good
# 太烫了到时候就也不好了
Make sure the water is not too hot
# 它就没有(嚼)劲了
The glass noodles will loose the chewiness
# 到时候泡了也不行
And soaking it won't help
# 稍微的剁一下
Chop it up slightly
# 别太短了
Not too short
# 太短了也不好
Make sure it is not too short
# 这时候咱们开始调味 盐
Now let's season. Some salt
# 这时候得放五香粉
Five spice
# 白胡椒去牛肉的膻味
White pepper to remove the gamey taste from beef
# 调馅大部分都离不开十三香
You usually need thirteen spice when making a dumpling filling
# 而且十三香的味道
And the aroma of thirteen spice
# 非常回味太香
lingers
# 浓厚
It is very rich
# 这时候咱们稍微加一点点水
Now let's add a tiny bit of water
# 给它和一下
Mix it in
# 咱今天买牛肉是干的
The beef today is dry
# 所以说 要不打一点水
If we don't mix in a bit of water
# 到时候裹不上
We might have a difficult time wrapping
# 咱先给它和开了
Mix it well
# 我还得加点香油和料酒
Adding in some Chinese cooking wine and sesame oil
# 黄酒 好嘞
Huangjiu rice wine. That's good.
# 其实这个馅儿没必要打上劲
You don't have to mix until sticky
# 和匀就行
As long as the ingredients are well integrated, it's fine
# 大家要做的时候
When you guys are making this at home
# 一定不要叫它太淡了
Make sure the filling is not too bland
# 因为外边还裹成一层面
Since there is a wrapper on the outside
# 加一点点酱油
Add a bit soy sauce
# 把这个馅
Add a bit moisture
# 和的滋润点
Into the filling
# 包了之后它成坨差不多了
As long as the filling is not falling apart after forming a ball, it is ready!
# 好 我们加点香油
Ok, now a little bit of sesame oil
# 好 如果说盐味到了调馅的时候
If you put enough salt into the filling
# 你放香油的时候
You should smell the aroma
# 就能闻到（味道）正好 香味出来了
When you put in the sesame oil
# 闻着都香
It smells so good
# 这个馅不能打上劲
Make sure to not overmix the filling
# 对 你看到了
Yea as you can see
# 你看它是慢慢捻的
He is turning it and mixing it slowly
# 最主要的就是什么
The most important thing about the filling
# 把肉裹着胡萝卜和粉条
Is making sure the carrot and glass noodles are covered by the mince
# 看 稍微半发就行了
The dough just have to rise half way
# 这时候咱们给它揪成小剂儿
Let's split the dough into smaller pieces
# 不需要太大 按剂儿的时候
Doesn't have to be too big. When flattening the dough pieces,
# 一定要投一个方向
Make sure to go for the same direction
# 揪着这个方向按下去
Press down on the cut side
# 包出来包子的时候比较光滑
So that the buns will be very smooth after wrapping
# 中间鼓四边薄
Thicker in the middle, thinner on the edges
# 包水煎包的时候
When you are wrapping the buns
# 皮薄馅稍微多一点
Make sure the wrapper is a bit thinner and add a bit more filling
# 这样咱们吃的好吃
Since it will taste better
# 一定捏着长饺
Pinch it by the longer edge
# 这饺 水煎饺
Wow this dumpling, pan fried dumpling
# 捏完以后
After sealing the buns
# 两边一定要给它
Make sure to pinch it on the edges
# 揪稍微长一点
Elongate it a bit
# 这样的话它看着
This way
# 包子比较大气
It will look more polished
# 好看 都包好了
That's all the wrapping
# 都包好了 师父
Yea we are done with the wrapping, Master
# 咱们先把汤给它调好
Let's make the slurry
# 生粉是一 面粉是二
1 part starch to 2 parts flour
# 这时候咱们加上水一定要稀一点
Let's add a bit water, make sure the liquid is a bit runny
# 别太稠了
And not too thick
# 太稠了等一下它有时候
If it is too thick,
# 就容易沾那个面锅
It will stick to the bottom of the pan very easily
# 粘的时候锅巴不亮
Then the Guo Ba, crust, will not be shiny
# 热锅凉油
Oil goes into the hot pan
# 就是先把锅给烧热
Heat up the pan first
# 放的时候一定要
When you are putting the buns in,
# 把角儿都给它对齐
Make sure the edges are aligned
# 出来的时候也好看
And when the dish comes out, it will be very pretty
# 二伯你看看 都听见滋啦啦的响
Erbai, look! You can hear the sizzling.
# 这时候就是什么
The next step
# 比如说水煎
Since we are doing Shui Jian, pan frying with water
# 就刚刚说了
Like we just said
# 咱们二合一的水汤
We have the two in one slurry
# 这个水有点少
This is probably not enough water
# 因为这个锅里边
Since the buns in the pan
# 因为咱今天包的有点大
are on the larger side
# 所以说可以多加一点点水
So we can add a bit more water
# 咱们大家在家里边做的时候
When you guys are cooking it at home
# 一定根据你包的水煎包的大小
You need to adjust the amount of water in the slurry
# 它的时间来确定水的量
Depending on the size and cooking time of your buns
# 比如你水少了
The buns might be uncooked
# 最后它不熟
If there is not enough water
# 它干了 水煎包
Yea, the pan will dry up. Pan fried buns
# 水煎包咱们叫饺
Buns but we call it dumplings
# 他们叫包
They call it buns
# 对
Yes
# 前期是咱们一定要是大火
Make sure to keep the heat on high at the beginning
# 后期最后收干的时候
And when we are reducing the liquid
# 再小火
Turn the heat to low
# 行 盖儿
Okay, lid on!
# 这样基本上大概在八分钟左右
This will probably take 8 minutes
# 小火8分钟
8 minutes on low heat
# 这时候咱们快
Now we have to move quickly
# 基本上冒泡的时候
As soon as it starts to bubble
# 快要干锅的时候
When the bottom is almost dry
# 咱们可以给一点点油
We can add a bit oil
# 这样的话色彩更好
To improve the color
# 好
Okay
# 就是说咱们这个火
Make sure the
# 一定要匀一点
heat is even
# 因为中间老是着中间就（糊了）
The buns might burn if the heat is always in the middle
# 所以说有时候在家里面
So you can make this with
# 用咱这电饼铛也能做
A Foreman grill at home
# 但是一定要把这个火
But make sure to be in control of the heat
# 一定要均匀 均匀的控制好
And heat up the buns evenly
# 不均匀的话
If it is uneven
# 它等于中间糊了两边发白
The dish will burn in the middle and the edges will be undercooked
# 这样出来以后
If we rotate the pan like this
# 咱们就全部都让它进来
All the pieces will have contact with heat
# 泡什么时候没了
The dish is ready
# 就好了
When the bubbles are gone
# 可以把四周的水分给烧干了
To dry out the moisture on the sides
# 面已经透亮 熟了
The bun looks clear, it is cooked
# 就差这底儿了
Now we are just waiting for the crispy bottom
# 来点香油出锅
A bit more sesame oil and we are ready to serve
# 出锅之后
Let's plate it
# 咱们给它摆盘
After taking it out of the pan
# 嚯够意思
WOW
# 漂亮
Gorgeous
# 您得先尝尝看馅儿
You should try the filling first
# 徒弟做的怎么样
How did your disciple do?
# 嗯 香 真香
Wow, delicious, so delicious
# 您吃的了一个吗
Can you finish one?
# 这个肉丸儿啊
The meat and
# 还有汤汁
The juice
# 十三香搁的好
The thirteen spice is perfect
# 十三香搁的好吧
I'm glad you like the thirteen spice
# 二伯尝尝
Try it, Erbai
# 您尝上面的锅巴是不是脆的
Is the Guo Ba crispy?
# 脆的 这时候脆不了了 都半天了
It might not be cripsy any more. It's been out of the pan for a while
# 这还真是脆的 锅巴是酥的
Wow it is still cripsy and also flaky
# 面呢
The wrapper?
# 很绵软
It is so soft
# 馅芯我看看
Let me look at the middle of the filling
# 你这皱眉头
Why are you frowning
# 我这心跳到这来了
My heart is all the way up here
# 是好吃的 还是好吃呢
Is it delicious or is it delicious?
# 徒弟在这等着
Your disciple is waiting here
# 心里面咯噔一下
Heart is racing
# 一皱眉头
When you
Frowned
# 这边吓一跳
He was so scared
# 对
Yea
# 烫了
It is a bit too hot
# 刚才您说了
You just said
# 这牛肉的膻味一点都吃不着
You can't taste the gamey beef smell at all
# 你看胡萝卜
Look at the carrot pieces
# 粉丝
Glass noodle
# 你别瞧 食材搭配简单
The ingredients are very easy
# 还有很实用
But very pragmatic
# 它五香粉和十三香是揉在一起的
The five spice and thirteen spice is integrated together
# 它出一种特殊效果
And brings out another flavour
# 要单出一味
If we only used one of the spices
# 味道它就不够
The flavour wouldn't be enough
# 二伯点到实处了
Erbai, you are on point!
# 好吃
So yummy!